Yashodeep Mahajan

Dublin | yasho.mahajan@gmail.com | +353 -892027358

www.linkedin.com/in/yashomahajan

Summary

Detailed oriented professional with 3.5+ years of experience in fintech and energy sector. Proven knowledge of work methods analysis with analytical thinking and process improvement. Aiming to grow skill sets and looking for challenging position in the organization.

Education

University of Limerick, MSc. in Business Analytics (2.1 Honours)

August 2024

University of Mumbai, B.E. in Mechanical engineering (2.1 Honours)

July 2019

Experience

Analyst, Insolutions Global - Mumbai, IN

Sept 2022 - Aug 2023

- Analyzed business data to identify trends, patterns, and insights that informed decision-making.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to gather, analyze, and document business requirements.
- Conducted business risk assessment, identified risk and developed risk mitigation strategies.
- Delivered 100 percent on-time progress and status reports to stakeholders, successfully identifying and escalating 30+ key risks and issues, establishing proactive resolution and project alignment.
- Analyzed and extracted key insights from structured and unstructured data, resulting in a 20 percent improvement in decision- making efficiency and driving actionable business strategies.
- Created detailed business requirements documents, improving project managers' and development teams' understanding of client requirements, resulting in a 25 percent reduction in project turnaround time.
- Managing change requests for the application system by doing detailed analysis.
- Conducted QA validation to ensure accuracy, consistency, and adherence to regulatory and corporate requirements.

Documentation Engineer, Citec Engineering India Pvt. Ltd. – Mumbai, IN

Jan 2020 – Sept 2022

- Prepared comprehensive plant operation manuals for Wärtsilä's energy business, ensuring clarity and adherence to industry standards.
- Developed installation and operation manuals for various power plant modules. Created maintenance manuals for Wärtsilä power plants.
- Performed data migration and conversion into clear, accessible formats for software configuration manuals for ABB. Master data collection for spare parts using SAP and Teamcenter and compilation of data and maintenance intervals of the modules and equipment (Life Cycle Management).
- Teamed up with the data management team to compile and organize documentation for 20+ projects, securing accuracy and consistency across all deliverables.
- Published over 200 comprehensive operation and maintenance manuals for Wärtsilä power plants and marine engines, assuring adherence to industry standards and client requirements.
- Coordinated closely with clients to ensure alignment on project goals and deliverables.

Intern, BRIT - Mumbai, IN

May 2018 - June 2018

• Skilled training at Boards of Radiation and Isotope Technology (BRIT/BARC)

Professional Skills

Tools and Technology: Python, R Studio, Power BI, Tableau, MySQL, Jira, Adobe Illustrator, Microsoft Office, CMS (Content Management System), Confluence, Document360, XML, SolidWorks, AutoCAD, MS Visio, SAP ERP

Soft Skills: Documentation, Data visualization, User requirement gathering, Data modelling, Data cleaning, Cross-functional collaboration, Stakeholder relationship management, Agile methodologies, Report writing, proofreading

Publications

Latent cooling system 2019

International Journal of Scientific and Engineering Research.

Solar thermal air conditioner using liquid desiccant dehumidification and IEC

Journal of Emerging Technologies and Innovative Research (JETIR 2019)

Projects

Healthcare Workflow Optimization Project

2024

2019

- The development of a cloud-based healthcare diagnostic platform that optimizes patient data analysis, resulting in quicker and more accurate diagnoses.
- Technology Used: Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Google Cloud Storage, Dataproc, BigQuery, Python, PySpark.

Centers Responsible for Climate Change

2023

- Analyzed the environmental impact of data centers by processing large datasets related to energy consumption
 and carbon emissions and utilized Power BI to create interactive dashboards and visualizations that
 demonstrated the correlation between data center operations and climate change.
- Technology Used: Power BI, Microsoft Office

Solar Thermal Air Conditioner

2019

 Developed a working hybrid cooling system combining latent and sensible cooling, utilizing tri-ethylene glycol as a desiccant.